Precious Ani

Software Engineer

Well-qualified Software Engineer, familiar with wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Handles any part of a development process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering 4+years of related experience.

Work History

2022-07 -Current

BackEnd Engineer

AfriHealth Tech Solutioins, Lagos

- Reviewed code, debugged problems and corrected issues
- Working on building REST API's using Laravel
- Working with Third Party Services to implemented technical solutions to real life problems

2022-01 -2022-06

FullStack Software Engineer

Bluecode Tech

- Reviewed code, debugged problems and corrected issues
- Conceived and built optimized landing pages in HTML and CSS
- Work on building and Consuming REST API's using Laravel for Backend and React JS for front-end.

2022-02 -2022-07

FullStack Software Engineer

Oxymon Solutions LTD, Lagos

- Managed the company web application and improved existing programming codes
- Integrated various Third party API's for various purposes on the application
- Led the Technical support team and worked as a standby Technical officer for the web application

2017-09 -2021-12

Backend Engineer

MeritInfos LLC, Enugu

 Managed company-level architecture, platform and data configuration processes and implementation protocols

Contact

Address

Obanikoro, Lagos Nigeria

Phone

08176157244

E-mail

anipreciousebuka@gmail.c om

Twitter

https://twitter.com /presh_dev

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com /in/precious-ebukaaa47181

www

https://preshdev.herokuap p.com/

Skills

Frontend Languages: HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT(AJAX, JQUERY, React JS, NextJS)

Backend Languages: PHP (Laravel, Codelgniter)

Tools & Dependency

Managers: Git, GitHub, Swagger UI, Composer, Postman

- Coordinated third-party vendors and client IT teams to seamlessly deliver effective solutions
- Developed and implemented long-term strategic technological blueprint

2021-01 - Full Stack Developer/Web Design Tutor 2021-12

Techocraft

- Reviewed code, debugged problems and corrected issues
- Delivered user support to clients to train, educate and answer questions
- Worked as a Web Design tutor in by introducing web engineering skills to next generation web experts.

Education

2015-09 -2019-10 Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

University of Nigeria - Enugu, Nigeria

Accomplishments

Completed Projects

- Oxymon: a financial empowerment web application, an application that automate the process of acquiring loan credits and setting up the payment structure (http://oxymon.co/);
- Copybee: a web application that helps content creators to create copies and content, using an Al copywriter, (https://copybee.io/);
- Netxropay: a crypto payment gateway web application(https://nextropay.com/);
- Buxiscrow: an Escrow payment system; (https://buxiscrow.co/);
- Constropal: a Construction Management Mobile application for Engineering contractors(https://constropal.com/);

Currently Running Projects

• EasyVtu: a virtual top up, web application and

mobile application, used to purchase airtime, internet, electricity, cable bills etcetera (https://github.com/Precious2804/easyVtu)

RigourPlus: a problem solving application,
targeted at providing E-commerce services for
Pharmacist, Tele-medicine services for Doctors
and Medical Practitioners, and also Ambulance
management services for Ambulance providing
companies and as well a Superadmin application
that manages the information on these
applications.

Interests

DevOps Engineering

Artificial Intelligence

Tech Business

Blockchain Technology